Melissa Piper

Front-End Web Developer

Pittsburgh, PA 412.377.5999 melissa.f.piper@gmail.com

LinkedIn: /in/melissapiper

Github: empee3

Website: melissapiper.com

I am a front-end developer with extensive experience developing for various industries, including higher education, nonprofits, service industries, and retail. I am an advocate for inclusiveness and accessibility throughout the web, and develop with the mindset that the internet is for everyone. I enjoy working on the subtle nuances that elevate a good website to a great website.

Skills

HTML, CSS, SASS, PHP, JavaScript, jQuery, Node.js, React, Drupal, WordPress, Git, Github, Docker, Webpack, Sketch, Figma, Storybook, JIRA, Basecamp, a11y

Experience

Sparkbox / Developer II

SEPTEMBER 2021 - FEBRUARY 2023, REMOTE

I contributed to the design system of a Fortune 500 company using React and Storybook. I also worked on major education and retail projects using Drupal and WordPress CMSes.

Elliance / Front-End Developer

AUGUST 2018 - AUGUST 2021, PITTSBURGH, PA

I developed and maintained the front-end of client websites, microsites, and landing pages, paying close attention to usability and accessibility.

Level Agency / Senior Front-End Developer

AUGUST 2017 - JULY 2018, PITTSBURGH, PA

I worked on RESTful API integration with major CRM platforms, including Netsuite and Infusionsoft. I also updated and maintained existing client and internal websites using WordPress. As a senior developer, I provided project estimates and POVs.

Beyond Spots & Dots / Drupal Developer

MAY 2014 - JULY 2017, PITTSBURGH, PA

I developed and maintained client and internal websites, primarily using Drupal. Most of my work focused on building new client websites, but I was also responsible for building and improving our custom-built internal project management system.

Education

California University of Pennsylvania

Graduate Certificate in Multimedia Technology

Bachelor of Science in Applied Computer Science